A Guide to the Papers of Harry Flood Byrd, Jr., 1813 (1936-1994) 1994
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Harry Flood Byrd, Jr., 1813 (1936-1994) 1994
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10320-e
This collection contains ca. 20,000 items (63 Hollinger boxes and 2 Oversize boxes, ca. 30 linear shelf feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the University of Virginia Library by Harry F. Byrd, Jr. of Winchester, Virginia, in November 1999.
Scope and Content Information
The papers of Harry F. Byrd, Jr., 1813, 1924-1994, ca. 20,000 items (63 Hollinger boxes and 2 Oversize boxes, ca. 30 linear shelf feet), contain news clippings; financial records, speeches, topical files, a scrapbook, memorabilia, correspondence; photographs; awards; plaques; certificates; political cartoons, including some by Fred O. Seibel; and 3 x 5 index cards pertaining to political campaign workers and managers for his 1966 and 1970 U.S. Senate races.
The papers contain files concerning the political campaigns of Harry F. Byrd, Jr., for the Virginia State Legislature and the United States Senate; working files from his terms in the Virginia and U.S. Senate; personal files; files pertaining to the Winchester Star and other family owned newspapers; files pertaining to the Byrd apple business; alphabetical files on political figures and Virginia politicians; and files on legislation considered in the Virginia Senate.
The majority of the files in this collection pertain to the life and career of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. However, material pertaining to Harry F. Byrd, Sr. is scattered throughout the collection and includes speeches, campaign files, financial papers and photographs. Particular boxes containing papers of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. are as follows: bank records (Box 21), estate papers (Box 26), stock correspondence (Box 29), photographs (Boxes 37-38 and OS Box T-14), his campaigns for U.S. Senate in 1946 and 1952 (Box 39 & OS Box S-56), and speeches (Box 40). There are also two notebooks, 1936, belonging to Harry F. Byrd, Sr., listing precinct workers and members of the Democratic committees of Virginia (Box 40).
Organization
Series I contains the alphabetically arranged correspondence of Harry F. Byrd, Jr., chiefly consisting of the following years, 1946-1949, 1955-1958, 1963-1965, and 1983- 1985. Topics vary but include correspondence of a personal, business, and political nature.
Series II contains papers of a financial or business nature, including the newspaper business, particularly the Daily News-Record, Page News and Courier, The Loudoun Times Mirror, and The Winchester Evening Star and the apple business. Topics dealing with the newspaper business range from advertising, the individual newspapers mentioned above, the Associated Press Board, the publisher representative De Lisser, Inc., Freedom of Information, the management consultant Youngs, Walker, & Company, and the Virginia Press Association.
General financial papers include some bank records of both Harry F. Byrd, Sr. and Harry F. Byrd, Sr. and Mrs. R.E. Byrd, papers concerning the estate of Harry F. Byrd, Sr., investment statements from Davenport & Company and White, Weld, & Company, and stock correspondence of Harry F. Byrd, Sr.
Files concerning the apple business include the apple cannery, the Bunker Hill Orchard, H.F.Byrd, Inc., Virginia Fruit Sales Manager James F. Laise, the Oakland Orchard, Richards Orchard, the Thurman Orchard, and Valley Fertilizer & Chemical Company, Inc.
Series III consists of photographs of the Byrd family, chiefly Harry F. Byrd, Jr. and Harry F. Byrd, Sr. and other personal papers of the Byrd family. These include articles written by Harry F. Byrd, Jr. as a newspaper editor, primarily noting the political and social conditions of various countries during the Cold War during trips to Europe, an article about Winston Churchill, and an article about political conventions for Look Magazine.
Correspondence files include letters from B. Beverley Byrd, Richard E. Byrd, and Thomas T. Byrd (included here in the personal series, although a great deal of the correspondence concerns H.F. Byrd, Inc. matters); the correspondence of Beverley Byrd Greenhalgh, daughter of Harry F. Byrd, Jr.; a single letter, October 11, 1813, from Anna Byrd to Richard H. Logan, discussing his recent letter to her daughter, Nancy; letters sent out by Byrd during the Christmas holidays; and the miscellaneous personal correspondence of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. which also discusses financial matters a good deal of the time.
Other files include news clippings re the controversy over the North Pole flight of Admiral Richard E. Byrd, "Courtfield Manor," Winchester, Virginia, correspondence with other members of the Reserve Officers of the Naval Services, Harry & Margaret Stimpson, and the University of Virginia.
Series IV, the largest single series, consists of the political papers in the collection and it has been subdivided into three Subseries: A) the Political Papers of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. B) the Political Papers of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. and C) the Files on Political Personages & Organizations kept by the Byrds. The political papers of Harry F. Byrd, Sr.(Boxes 39-40) are chiefly concerned with his Democratic primary campaigns for United States Senate in 1946 and in 1952, including absentee ballots, news clippings re the campaign, correspondence and memoranda, statements and speeches.
The political papers of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. (Boxes 41-54) are chiefly concerned with his tenure in the Virginia state Senate, 1947-1965, although there are a few files pertaining to his service in the U.S. Senate, including his files for Senate staff members (see U.S. Senate Staff of Harry F. Byrd, Jr.) and a few case files (see Correspondence and case name). These include folders on annual sessions; appropriations and taxes; the budget; his political campaigns for the Virginia state Senate in 1947, 1959, and 1963; constituent letters about a variety of topics, especially urging him to run for Governor in 1960; education; the Gray Commission Report; Highways; Industrial Development; files on most Legislative Sessions and Special Sessions (including segregation, redistricting, sales tax, and the poll tax; the Outdoor Recreation Commission; Poll Tax Resolution; Redistricting; School Board Bill; School Policy Study Commission; Sales Tax; speeches; the Tax Reduction Bill; the Virginia 350th Anniversary Commission; and Workmen?s Compensation.
The political personages and organizations files (Boxes 54-62) found in Subseries C contain folders on individual Virginia politicians, both friends and foes of the Byrd machine. They are alphabetically arranged, with some politicians having several folders which are divided into miscellaneous categories such as correspondence, speeches or statements, campaigns, and news clippings. For a full listing of these individuals, see the box listing for boxes 54-62.
Also represented here are the Virginia governors, J. Lindsay Almond, Jr.; John Stewart Battle; Colgate Darden; Mills E. Godwin, Jr.; Albertis Sydney Harrison, Jr.; Thomas B. Stanley; William M. Tuck; and U.S. Senators Paul Trible and A.Willis Robertson.
Series V consists of any oversize materials and miscellaneous items, including plaques awarded to Harry F. Byrd, Jr.; political cartoons by Fred Seibel and other cartoonists; large photographs of Byrd and other politicians, some autographed; drawings; certificates of award; a scrapbook of news clippings pertaining to Harry F. Byrd, Sr.; maps; blueprints; and plats. For these oversize materials see Box 63 (plaques), Oversize Box T-14, Oversize Box S-56, Oversize Tray #18 and the Seibel Cartoon Collection.
Series I: Correspondence, alphabetically arranged (Boxes 1-19)
Series II: Financial & Business Papers (Boxes 20-31)
Series III: Photographs & Personal Papers (Boxes 32- 38)
Series IV: Political Papers (Boxes 39-62)
Subseries A: Political Papers of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. (Boxes 39-40)
Subseries B: Political Papers of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. Chiefly During his Service as a Virginia State Senator (Boxes 41-54)
Subseries C: Files on Political Personages & Organizations (Boxes 54-62)
Series V: Miscellaneous Items
Subseries A: Plaques Awarded to Harry F. Byrd, Jr. (Box 63)
Subseries B: Political Cartoons (OS Box T-14 & Seibel Cartoons)
Subseries C: Photographs & Other Oversize Items (OS Box T-14 & OS Box S-56)
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence - A 1946-1949 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - A 1955-1958, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - A 1963-1965, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - A 1983-1985 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - B 1946-1949 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - B 1955-1958, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - B 1963-1964, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - B 1965, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - B 1975-1986, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - C 1946-1949, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - C 1955-1958, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - C 1963-1965, 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Correspondence - C 1983-1985, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Correspondence - D 1946-1949 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence - D 1955-1958, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Correspondence - D 1963-1965, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Correspondence - D 1983-1985 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence - E 1945-1949, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence - E 1956-1958 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence - E 1963-1965, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Correspondence - E 1982-1985 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence - F 1946-1949 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence - F 1955-1958, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Correspondence - F 1963-1965, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Correspondence - F 1983-1985, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Correspondence - G 1945-1949 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence - G 1955-1958, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Correspondence - G 1963-1965, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Correspondence - G 1981-1986, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Correspondence - H 1945-1949 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence - H 1955-1958, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Correspondence - H 1963-1965, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Correspondence - H 1982-1985, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Correspondence - I 1945-1965, 1983-1985 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence - J 1945-1949 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence - J 1955-1958 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence - J 1963-1965 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence - J 1982-1985 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence - K 1945-1949, 1955-1956 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence - K 1957-1958 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence - K 1963-1965 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence - K 1982-1986 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence - L 1945-1949 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence - L 1955-1958, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Correspondence - L 1963-1965, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Correspondence - L 1982-1985 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence - M 1945-1949, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Correspondence - M 1955-1957, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Correspondence - M 1958 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence - M 1963-1965, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Correspondence - M 1982-1985 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence - Mc 1962-1965, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Correspondence - Mc 1983-1986 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence - N 1945-1949, 1955 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence - N 1956-1958 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence - N 1963-1965 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence - N 1983-1985 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence - O 1945-1965, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Correspondence - O 1983-1985 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence - P 1945-1949 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence - P 1956-1958 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence - P 1963-1964, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Correspondence - P 1965 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence - P 1983-1985 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence - Q 1947-1983 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence - R 1945-1949, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Correspondence - R 1955-1958, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Correspondence - R 1963-1964, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Correspondence - R 1965 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence - R 1983-1985 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence - S 1945-1949, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Correspondence - S 1955-1958, 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Correspondence - S 1962-1965, 6 folders (Box 16)
  - Correspondence - S 1983-1985, 1 of 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Correspondence - S 1983-1985, 2 of 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Correspondence - T 1945-1949 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence - T 1955-1958, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Correspondence - T 1963-1965, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Correspondence - T 1983-1985 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence - U 1941-1984 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence - V 1945-1985, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Correspondence - W 1945-1949, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Correspondence - W 1955-1958, 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Correspondence - W 1962-1963, 1 of 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Correspondence - W 1962-1963, 2 of 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Correspondence - W 1964-1965, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Correspondence - W 1982-1985, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Correspondence - X-Y-Z 1956-1985 (Box 19)
- Financial & Business Papers
  - Advertising 1946-1955 (Box 20)
  - The Advertising Council 1952-1954 (Box 20)
  - Apple Cannery 1966-1970, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Associated Press 1959-1965, n.d., 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Associated Press Board 1950-1956 (Box 20)
  - Associated Press Board 1957-1958 (Box 21)
  - Associated Press Parties 1956-1965 (Box 21)
  - Bank Records - Harry F. Byrd, Sr. (Farmers & Merchants National Bank) 1942-1966 (Box 21)
  - Bank Records - Mrs. R.E. Byrd 1945-1955 (Box 21)
  - Bank Registers 1963-1964, 2 volumes (Box 21)
  - Bank Statements of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. 1953-1954 (Box 21)
  - Bank Statements of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. 1955-1964, 5 folders (Box 22)
  - Building Tenants 1949-1958 (Box 22)
  - Bunker Hill Orchards & Marvin E. Williams, Jr. (Partner) 1965-1973, 1979 (Box 22)
  - Community Antenna Television System 1964 (Box 22)
  - Daily News-Record 1952-1963, 1967-1969, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Daily News-Record 1970-1973, 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Daily News-Record Leadership Award 1955-1973, 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Daily News-Record Stockholders 1924, 1944-1973, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Davenport & Company ca. 1945-1963, 9 folders (Box 24)
  - Davenport & Company 1964-1973, 6 folders (Box 25)
  - De Lisser, Inc. 1947-1955 (Box 25)
  - The El Paso Times Publication Committee 1962-1963 (Box 26)
  - Estate of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. 1963-1970, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Estate of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. - Protest and Exhibits 1969 Sep 18 (Box 26)
  - Freedom of Information 1953-1954 (Box 26)
  - H.F. Byrd, Inc. 1949-1955, 1966-1968, 3 folders (Box 26)
  - H.F. Byrd, Inc. 1969-1973, 3 folders (Box 27)
  - H.F. Byrd, Inc. - Correspondence of Harry F. Byrd III 1966-1973 (Box 27)
  - H.F. Byrd, Inc. - Mortgage 1947, 1952-1954 (Box 27)
  - Income Tax Information 1953-1962 (Box 27)
  - Industrial Rayon Corporation 1952-1961 (Box 27)
  - Insurance - Car & Personal Property ca. 1949-1965 (Box 27)
  - Insurance - Health 1959-1965 (Box 27)
  - Insurance - House and Building Casualty ca. 1945-1965 (Box 28)
  - Insurance - Life 1945-1967, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - James F. Laise, Virginia Fruit Sales Manager 1966-1970, 1973 (Box 28)
  - Loudoun Times Mirror 1962 (Box 28)
  - National Conference of Editorial Writers 1947 (Box 28)
  - Oakland Orchard 1955-1968, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Page News and Courier 1964-1973, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Page Newspaper Corporation - Reports 1968-1970 (Box 28)
  - Pledges 1961-1982, 4 folders (Box 29)
  - Pyramid 13 1957-1965 (Box 29)
  - Richards Orchard 1939-1942 (Box 29)
  - Roosevelt Der Tatevasion, Publisher 1966-1968, 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Stock Correspondence of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. 1958-1966 (Box 29)
  - Thurman Orchard - Correspondence 1954-1967 (Box 29)
  - Thurman Orchard - Costs & Production 1955-1959 (Box 30)
  - Thurman Orchard - Crop 1950-1963 (Box 30)
  - Thurman Orchard - Growth Charts 1938-1951 (Box 30)
  - Thurman Orchard - Lease & Payroll 1937-1946 (Box 30)
  - Thurman Orchard - Mortgage 1959-1968 (Box 30)
  - Valley Fertilizer & Chemical Company, Inc. 1965-1969 (Box 30)
  - Virginia Press Association, Inc. 1945-1955 (Box 30)
  - White, Weld, & Company 1953-1959, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Winchester Evening Star 1952-1955 (Box 30)
  - Winchester Evening Star 1966-1970, 3 folders (Box 30)
  - Winchester Evening Star 1971-1973, 1977-1982, 5 folders (Box 31)
  - Winchester Evening Star Leadership Award 1954-1973 (Box 31)
  - Winchester Evening Star- Report 1960 Nov 30 (Box 31)
  - Youngs, Walker, & Company 1978-1982 (Box 31)
- Photographs & Personal Papers
  - Apple Blossom Festival 1937-1955, 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Article by Harry F. Byrd, Jr. "The Churchill I Knew" 1965 Jan 16 (Box 32)
  - Article by Harry F. Byrd, Jr. "Conventions I Have Known" in Look Magazine- Research Materials ca. 1948-1961 (Box 32)
  - Article by Harry F. Byrd, Jr. "Conventions I Have Known" in Look Magazine- Typescripts and Print Version 1960 (Box 32)
  - Biographical Information re Harry F. Byrd, Jr. 1965, n.d. (Box 32)
  - Anna Byrd to Richard H. Logan, discussing his recent letter to her daughter, Nancy 1813 Oct 11 (Box 32)
  - B. Beverley Byrd - Correspondence 1967-1973, 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Richard E. Byrd - Correspondence 1966-1973, 3 folders (Box 33)
  - Thomas T. Byrd - Correspondence 1968-1973, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Car 1961-1965 (Box 33)
  - Cartoon Drawing of "Ma Winchester" 1945 Sep 27 (Box 33)
  - Christmas Letters & Apples 1945-1949 (Box 33)
  - Christmas Letters 1950-1966, n.d., 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Christmas Lists 1963-1973 (Box 34)
  - "Courtfield Manor," Winchester, Virginia 1948-1970 (Box 34)
  - European Trips of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. 1948-1965, n.d., 4 folders (Box 34)
  - European Trips of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - News clippings ca. 1951-1955, 1962 (Box 34)
  - Beverley Byrd Greenhalgh 1968-1973 (Box 34)
  - Charles Evans Hughes (not the jurist) Crank Letters 1959-1970 (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Personal Correspondence, including some financial matters ca. 1935-1973, 7 folders (Box 35)
  - Names and Addresses in Old File 1945-1949 (Box 36)
  - News clippings re the Controversy over the North Pole Flight of Admiral Richard E. Byrd 1971 (Box 36)
  - News clippings re Harry F. Byrd, Jr. 1935-1947, 1965, 1971, n.d. (Box 36)
  - Newsday Correspondence re the Democratic National Convention Coverage by Harry F. Byrd, Jr. 1964 (Box 36)
  - New York Trips 1955-1965 (Box 36)
  - Photographs 1950-1981, n.d. (Box 36)
    Autographed by Notables, including General Omar Bradley, Jim Bueler, Warren E. Burger, R.E. Byrd, Jerry Ford, Burr Harrison, Jesse Helms, Lyndon Baines Johnson, Curtis L. May (Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff), Nancy Reagan, Governor Thomas B. Stanley, and William M. Tuck.
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. ca. 1965-1967, n.d., (8 x 10) and (6 ½ x 8) (Box 36)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. ca. 1965-1975, n.d., (5 x 7 and smaller) (Box 36)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Awards, Banquets & Meetings ca. 1970-1981, n.d. (Box 36)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Family ca. 1964-1981, n.d. (Box 36)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Festivals ca. 1975-1980 (Box 36)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Foreign Notables ca. 1975-1980 (Box 36)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Graduations 1982, n.d. (Box 36)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Groups of People (Unidentified) ca. 1971-1981, n.d. (Box 36)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Military Setting or Personnel 1966-1976 (Box 36)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Miscellaneous 1966-1974, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Presidents 1964-1981 (Box 37)
    See also "Photographs - Autographed by Notables" for more photographs of Byrd with Presidents
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - at the Senate 1966-1970, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Ship Dedications ca. 1971-1980 (Box 37)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Speaking at Miscellaneous Events 1965-1975, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - U.S. Politicians 1952-1981, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Virginia Politicians 1956-1980, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Virginia State Senate and Earlier Career ca. 1937-1965, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. 1926-1965, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. (with Negatives) 1963, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. - Portraits & Statue 1988, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Printed Material ca. 1939-1941 (Box 38)
  - Reserve Officers of the Naval Services 1945-1948, 3 folders (Box 38)
  - "Rosemont," Berryville, Virginia, Etching of the home of Mr. & Mrs. Richard E. Byrd n.d. (Box 38)
  - "A Salute to Senator Harry F. Byrd, Jr. for distinguished service" Program 1982 Dec 6 (Box 38)
  - Richard T. Short ca. 1969-1981 (Box 38)
  - Slides of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. and Family n.d. (Box 38)
  - Harry & Margaret Stimpson 1973-1982 (Box 38)
  - Tax Foundation 1960-1965 (Box 38)
  - University of Virginia 1946-1955 (Box 38)
- Political Papers
  - Political Papers of Harry F. Byrd, Sr.
    - Absentee Ballots - Virginia Election for U.S. Senate 1946-1947 (Box 39)
    - Campaign of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. for the U.S. Senate 1946-1947, n.d., 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Campaign of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. for the U.S. Senate - Advertising 1946-1947 (Box 39)
    - Campaign of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. for the U.S. Senate - Democratic Primary Result 1946 (Box 39)
    - Campaign of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. for the U.S. Senate -Advertisements & Publicity 1952 (Box 39)
    - Campaign of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. for the U.S. Senate - Campaign Managers & Statement of Expenses 1952 (Box 39)
    - Campaign of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. for the U.S. Senate - Correspondence & Memoranda 1952 (Box 39)
    - Campaign of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. for the U.S. Senate - Districts 1-10 1952, 4 folders (Box 39)
    - Campaign of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. for the U.S. Senate - A.S. Harrison, Jr 1952 (Box 39)
    - Campaign of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. for the U.S. Senate - News clippings 1952 (Box 39)
    - Campaign of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. for the U.S. Senate - Statements Issued by Persons Other than Senator Byrd 1952 (Box 39)
    - Loose-Leaf Notebook containing the names of Precinct Workers by District 1936 (Box 40)
    - Loose-Leaf Notebook containing the names of the Democratic Committee members by District 1936 (Box 40)
    - Speeches of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. ca. 1946-1955, 1964, 6 folders (Box 40)
    - Third Term Resolution re the Presidency ca. 1947-1948 (Box 40)
  - Political Papers of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. Chiefly During His Service as a Virginia State Senator
    - Advisory Legislative Council 1962 (Box 41)
    - Annual Sessions - Editorial Comment 1950 (Box 41)
    - Annual Sessions - Resume of Legislation re, 1950-1960 ca. 1960 (Box 41)
    - Appropriations & Taxes 1960 Jan-Mar, 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Budget 1948-1962, 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Campaign of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. for the Virginia Senate 1946-1947, 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Campaign of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. for the Virginia Senate 1959 & 1963 (Box 41)
    - Constituent Letters ca. 1947-1964, 4 folders (Box 41)
    - Constituent Letters re Auto Sales Tax 1964 (Box 42)
    - Constituent Letters re Byrd's Statement about Federal Judge John D. Butzner & the Powhatan County School Case 1963, 3 folders (Box 42)
    - Constituent Letters urging Byrd to run for Governor 1959-1960, 4 folders (Box 42)
    - Constituent Letters re Byrd's decision not to run for Governor Districts 1-4 1960 (Box 42)
    - Constituent Letters re Byrd's decision not to run for Governor Districts 5-10 1960 (Box 43)
    - Constituent Letters re Sales Tax 1959-1961, 5 folders (Box 43)
    - Constituent Letters from Teachers 1960 (Box 43)
    - Correspondence - Lynn M. Brown (PFC) 1982-1983 (Box 44)
    - Correspondence - Sgt. Lonnie W. Jackson 1981-1984 (Box 44)
    - Correspondence - Helen Marie Taylor 1983 (Box 44)
    - Correspondence with members of the Legislature 1948 & 1950, 2 folders (Box 44)
    - Correspondence with members of the Legislature following the end of session 1958 (Box 44)
    - Education 1948-1961 (Box 44)